# **Khadim Hussain**

# iOS Developer

Business Bay, Dubai - UAE Contact No: +971 56 9147945 E-mail: m.khadim012@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/khadim-hussain-%EF%A3%BF-82386685/



A pioneering developer offering more than 7 years' experience designing, implementing, integrating, testing and supporting impact-full applications developed in diverse, collaborative environments with latest trends for mobile and tablet devices on the iOS platform.

### CORE STRENGTHS & ENABLING SKILLS

- Swift / SwiftUI
- Objective C
- XCode
- iOS VIPER, MVC, MVVM design patterns

- Socket.io
- Alamofire, Afnetworking
- AR kit
- Google, Mapbox and Apple Maps

- Firebase APIs/FCM Crashlytics, BugSnag
  - Crashlytics, BugSnagOneSignal, NetCore
- Cocoa PodsiOS Widgets
- SQLite and Core Data databases.Apple payment, Wallet, PayPal, Checkout.

- Stripe PaymentTwilio, Quickblox
- Codable, ObjectMapper
- Social SDKs
- Beacons Broadcasting/Receivers (BLE)

# PROFESSIONAL QUALIFICATION

BS Computer Science - 2012 - 2016

The University of Lahore (UOL) Lahore, Pakistan

■ Fsc. Pre-Engineering - 2010 – 2012

Punjab Group of Colleges, Hafizabad, Punjab, Pakistan

■ Matriculation - 2008 – 2010

Govt. Higher Secondary School Jalalpur Bhattian, Punjab, Pakistan

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Life Pharmacy (Management Office), Business Bay - Dubai, UAE.

**NOV 2021 ---- PRESENT** 

Available on AppStore: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/life-pharmacy//id1450835575">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/life-pharmacy//id1450835575</a>

#### **Technologies and Computer Language used:**

XCode, Swift, VIPPER, UIKit, ObjectMapper, OneSignal, JIRA, Netcore, GitHub, Adjust, Bugsnag, Deep linking.

- -Rendered responsibilities as "Senior iOS Application Developer"
- Develops Life Pharmacy applications for mobile devices powered by Apple's iOS operating system.
- Follow up and meet the deadlines.
- Ensures the top performance, quality, and responsiveness of applications.
- Corrects bottlenecks, fixes bugs, improves organization and automation.
- Defines, designs, and ships new features for the iOS platform

## ZIRO, Business Bay - Dubai, UAE Office/Head Office in USA San francisco.

Working as "Senior iOS Developer", October 2018 - November 2021

- iOS team lead.
- Manage multiple applications.
- Follow up and meet the deadlines.

### iOS Applications for Mobile/iPad Devices

#### NEWSREELS

Available on AppStore: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/newsreels-discover-top-news/id1540932937

Newsreels is a news app that chops the clutter from news articles and give the real-time news in one place.

It personalized news aggregator app that allows you to filter the news stories according to the topics you like, from the publications you want.

#### ZIRO RIDER

Available on AppStore: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1459524702?ls=1">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1459524702?ls=1</a>

It is a riding app for the user side. it includes searching near drivers, Scheduling trips, drawing a path on the map, socket for vehicle movement on the map, AR to find the driver location, Live video streaming, BLE for gaming Remote, Voice recognition for safety help, Sharing live trip, Subscription plan, Stripe payment, Apple payment, Referral program, Community chat, Reviews and Ratings.

#### ZIRO CAPTAIN

Available on AppStore: https://apps.apple.com/us/app/id1459525297?ls=1

Ziro Captain is a driving app for the drivers side. It includes trip requests, Map navigation, drawing a path on the map, socket, Live video streaming, Voice recognition for safety help, Stripe payment, Apple payment, Referral program, Community chat, Reviews and Ratings.

#### NXPLAY.R

Available on AppStore: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/nxplay-r-1-football-community/id1603418784">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/nxplay-r-1-football-community/id1603418784</a>

The idea is simple: we are working hard to develop the largest football community ever created, a 'real' LinkedIn but entirely dedicated to football where an infinite number of opportunities would be created for everyone!

## Soloinsight Inc. Lahore Office/Head Office in USA CHICAGO.

Working as "iOS Developer", September 2016 – October 2018

## iOS Applications for Mobile/iPad Devices

#### CloudGate

Available on AppStore: <a href="https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cloudgate/id1143004311?mt=8">https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cloudgate/id1143004311?mt=8</a>

Cloud Gate! APP includes enrolment, registration, usage, access and reporting, interacting with beacons to mark attendance via BLE, it is user base application that detect Beacons to mark attendance, Keep the record of enrolled users and attendance.

Broadcasting BLE, Receiving BLE, Nearby users, Nearby Devices, Generate QR-Code, Fingerprint sensor. Scan Barcode and QR-Code, SQLite Database to store data locally.

# CloudGate-Lite

Sync all data in local dB and scan the QR code. If the scanned user pass is not expired then mark the attendance by QR code. There is also option to mark attendance through BLE. When the user marked the attendance then open the relay to unlock the door lock.

### CloudGate-Visitor

Cloud Gate-Visitor! This application is used for invitation, send QR pass, visiting time and the access points of visitor. Works with JSON data, Web views, SQLite database, Auto layouts for universal design.

#### CloudGate Mobility

Developed dynamic views for iPad. User can mark their attendance by showing their QR-Code or through BLE.

# CloudGate Enterprise

Updated version or customized version of the cloudgate application according to the requirement of Microsoft.

#### CloudGate Notification

Dashboard application for drivers. Push notifications, APIs integration, third party libraries, AFNetworking.

### CloudGate Mobile Check-In

In this app user can view all the invited visitors and he can also invite more visitors. User can also print the badge for any visitor. User can also get details from driver license by scanning barcodes and check validity if the pass is valid then print the badge otherwise show pass expired. While scanning if the scanned user is in watchlist then prompt the user by showing dialog.

# **Brand Impact – Silicon Oasis, Dubai – UAE.**

November 2019 - November 2020

iOS Application Developer (Remotely)

### GiftyOnlineUAE

Available on AppStore: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/giftyonlineuae/id1538811911">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/giftyonlineuae/id1538811911</a>

Gifty Online is your gateway to a world of wonderful products, all at incredibly low prices. With all your favorite brands available at hand, and not to mention the tons of deals up for grabs.

#### Pets Health

Available on AppStore: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pets-health/id1508992699">https://apps.apple.com/us/app/pets-health/id1508992699</a>

Pets Health Veterinary Clinic FZE offers a totally unique online retail experience for the Middle East. Born in 2019, Pets Health Veterinary Clinic FZE has a vast product selection, including not only premium pet food and carefully selected pet accessories but also high quality veterinary approved medications and supplements delivered right at your doorstep wherever you are in the United Arab Emirates.

## Quote Catalog

**Available on AppStore:** https://apps.apple.com/us/app/quote-catalog/id1403987051

QuoteCatalog can help you quickly capture quotes (via typing, talking it into your device, or taking a picture), organize quotes (by speaker, topic, or book), and find quotes (by keyword) so that you can find the right quote at the right time every time!

#### InfoSense Mobile

Available on AppStore: <a href="https://apps.apple.com/ae/app/infosense-mobile/id1302786369">https://apps.apple.com/ae/app/infosense-mobile/id1302786369</a>

InfoSense Mobile is a reliable GPS Tracking App with an easy-to- use interface that allows you to monitor your vehicles and assets right from your mobile. The app is designed and developed by Informap, UAE and the tracking service is being used by 1000+ companies in the UAE and several others in the GCC and elsewhere.

#### Gazelle

Gazelle is multi language app used to frames your image and can order of your image with user favorite frame.

#### HomeBiz

HomeBiz is a food delivery application based on Dubai UAE.

# Buggz, Lahore – Pakistan

**June 2017 – September 2018** 

iOS Application Developer (Remotely)

• World Cup 2018 Russia Live: <a href="https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wcfreeunofficial.com">https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.wcfreeunofficial.com</a>

The app offers the following interactive live features: Live Scores, Groups, Fixtures & Schedules, Goal Notifications, Polls, Fan Chat, Schedules of Group Matches, Work on Adds, show full screen ads and banner.

### Gosseeum

This application is used to find people from different fields. Work on google maps, JSON data. Fetching data from web server, Web views, SQLite database for offline mode, Auto layouts for universal design, Work on table view, collection view and Scroll view.

### DoctorWho

This application is used for a consultant with doctors, Registration of doctors, pharmacist, Medical Store.